VINIT KUMAR



DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Signify Innovations India Limited, Bengaluru INDIA.

A results-driven, customer-focused, articulate Senior Development Engineer who can think "out of the box". Strong in design and integration of problem-solving skills. Having 12+ years of overall experience in Android, Java, Kotlin, Flutter, Data Structure, Database, and leading Android team with 6 to 8 Mobile App Developers.

Contact

VinitKr28@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/vinitkr/ +91 96113333500 Bengaluru, INDIA.

Education

SRI SATYA SAI UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY & MEDICAL SCIENCES, SEHORE, MP, INDIA.

Master of Technology in Computer Science And Engineering 2021-2023

Skills

Android App. Development

Flutter App. Development

Fundamental of iOS App Dev.

Java, Kotlin, Dart, Swift

Scrum Master

Mobile App. Testing, Automation & Release Process

Experience

DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER SIGNIFY INNOVATIONS INDIA LTD

September 2020 – Till Now

Successfully leading teams through the development of several high-profile mobile applications, resulting in increased user engagement by 30%.

Spearheading the migration of legacy systems to modernized mobile platforms, improving application stability and user experience.

Collaborating closely with cross-functional teams including UX/UI designers, product managers, and QA testers to deliver products that meet both technical and business requirements.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II HONEYWELL TECHNOLOGY SOL. LAB PVT. LTD

August 2016 - September 2020

Led the Mobile app development team, resulting in a 25% increase in app downloads on the Play Store. Established CI-CD, automation which decrease the app testing time by 30%. I mentored a team member and increased their productivity by approximately 20%.

SENIOR ENGINEER TATA ELXSI PVT LTD

February 2016 - July 2016

Developed a social media mobile app for LivingTree that has been downloaded more than 2 million times. We used analytics and Firebase to increase the app's performance by 20%.